<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_lite.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="m"><hi rend="italic">Transcription of a Page from Huntington MS 924</hi></title>
            <title level="a"><hi rend="italic">Walden Drafts</hi></title>
            <author>Henry David Thoreau</author>
           <editor>Dani Gottfried</editor>
                        
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Transcribed and Encoded By</resp>
               <name>Dani Gottfried</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
      
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Not for public circulation.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc>
            <p><bibl><author>Thoreau, Henry David.</author> <title level="a">Walden Material from Huntington MS 924</title>.<biblScope unit="vol">5</biblScope> <biblScope unit="page">166</biblScope>
               
               <date type="earliest" when="1852">1852</date><date type="latest" when="1853">1853</date>
               <ref type="URL">https://cdm16003.contentdm.oclc.org/digital/collection/p16003coll16/id/833</ref>
                             </bibl>
            </p>
                   </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
     <encodingDesc>
        <p>Transcribed from HM 924 and encoded in XML in accordance with the TEI Guidelines.</p>
     </encodingDesc>
     <profileDesc>
        <langUsage>
           <language ident="en">English</language>
        </langUsage>
     </profileDesc>
     <revisionDesc>
     <list><item><date when="2017-11-26" resp="#rnes">26 Nov 2017</date>Encoding shell drafted.</item>
        <item><date when="2020-09-27">27 September 2020</date>Filled in the header</item>
        <item><date when="2020-09-28">28 September 2020</date>Transcribed the text</item>
        </list>
     </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div type="volume" n="5">
            <div type="page" n="166">
               <p>
                  <del><hi rend="grey pencil">witch-like</hi></del><add><hi rend="grey pencil">inhumane</hi></add>. One old frequenter <add><hi rend="grey pencil">P. 398-9</hi></add>of these woods remembers that as he passed her house one <del>day</del> noon, he heard her muttering to herself over her gurgling pot "Ye are all bones - bones." <add><hi rend="grey pencil">I have seen bricks amid the oak copse there.</hi></add></p>
                <p> And down the road on the right hand on Brister's Hill lived Brister Freeman a, "handy negro" slave of Squire Cummings once, there where grow still the apple trees which Brister planted and tended, large old trees but still wild + childish to my taste. Not long since I read his epitaph in the <add rend="carot"></add><add><hi rend="grey pencil">old</hi></add>Lin- <add><hi>a little on one side near the unmarked graves of <del>Br</del>British gren</hi></add> coln burying ground where <add><hi rend="grey pencil">adiers who fell in the retreat from concord</hi></add>he is styled "Sippio Brister" Scipio Africanus he had some title to be called - "a man of color" as if he were discolored. It also told me when he died, but that seemed <add rend="carot"></add><add>but</add>an indi- rect way of informing me that he ever lived. And there <add><hi rend="grey penci">too lived</hi></add><del><hi rend="grey pencil">was</hi></del> Fenda, his hopitable
                 
                 
                 
                 
                 
              </p>
            
            </div>
            </div>

         
      </body>
     <back>
        <p>Critical Commentary</p><!--paste your critical commentary within the paragraph tags below. You may add additional paragraphs if you wish. By now, you should know how.-->
     <p>                            
        Transcribing Thoreau’s original work I found to be a fascinating but extremely difficult project. First, I printed out the facsimile photo of the original writing. I used this to work by hand to decipher what was written. The original handwriting was very difficult to read, so I compared it to a later print version I have of the text. As I compared the two, I wrote under each word what it seemed to read. I entered this into the XML file and tagged the transcription to the best of my ability before repeating the process with the markings done in pencil on the text. Prior to this project, I knew coding to be difficult. However, I have discovered a whole new appreciation for transcribing and encoding. I often struggled with the XML file as I tried to learn the proper way to encode a certain section or correct a mistake. I would think I had everything figured out just to stumble again on my next attempt. I was very grateful for the validation box in the upper righthand corner of the program that would instantly alert me when I made a mistake. I also appreciated the notes that would appear at the bottom of the program to inform me specifically what the mistake was. These two features significantly helped me navigate my first attempt at transcribing. </p>
      <p>  Through this project, I’ve started to grasp an understanding of just how large the TEI is. It’s something I was completely unaware of prior to this assignment. It must take an unfathomable number of hours for people to transcribe and encode entire works. I know my single page took several hours even when working with a template provided to me to jumpstart my progress. Additionally, I’m sure the work I did produce is not nearly as refined and detailed as the work other people in the TEI community produce. I didn’t understand the extent of how much time, effort, and skill went into transcription and encoding, and this new knowledge has also brought a new respect for the work the TEI is doing. </p>
       <p> In addition to learning significantly more about transcription than I ever thought I would know, I gained a whole new perspective of Thoreau. I especially loved learning how to read his handwriting. When I first attempted to read his writing, I struggled to make out a single word on the entire page. However, after comparing the original work to modern-day editions to study how Thoreau wrote each word and letter, I found myself able to read his penmanship completely on my own. I also really enjoyed seeing how the writing evolved after so many years. I wasn’t surprised to find differences between Thoreau’s original writing and the recent text edition of it. However, it was interesting to see exactly what had been changed over the years. In fact, I found it most interesting to see what hadn’t changed. I probably shouldn’t have been surprised to find most of Thoreau’s original words have survived to read in modern day texts exactly as he wrote them. Save for a few lines or words here and there, the original writing I was transcribing and the text I was comparing it to were nearly identical. </p>
        <p>This process of transcribing and encoding a page from Thoreau’s has taught me I have a lot yet to learn when it comes to the TEI. I don’t think I could ever professionally pursue transcription and encoding, but I’ve enjoyed learning the process and gaining some beginner skills. I’m glad I have a basic knowledge of the world of TEI should I ever encounter it at some point in my career path.
        
     
     
     
     
     
     
     
     </p>
     </back>
  </text>
</TEI>