<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_lite.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="m"><hi rend="italic">Transcription of a Page from Huntington MS 924</hi></title>
            <title level="a"><hi rend="italic">Walden Drafts</hi></title>
            <author>Henry David Thoreau</author>
           <editor>Kaitlyn Pichette</editor>
                        
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Transcribed and Encoded By</resp>
               <name>Kaitlyn Pichette</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
      
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Not for public circulation.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         
         <sourceDesc>
            <p><bibl><author>Thoreau, Henry David.</author> <title level="a">Walden Material from Huntington MS 924</title>.<biblScope unit="vol">5</biblScope><biblScope unit="page">165</biblScope>
               
               <date type="earliest" when="1852">1852</date><date type="latest" when="1853">1853</date>
                             </bibl>
            </p>
                   </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
     <encodingDesc>
        <p>Transcribed from HM 924 and encoded in XML in accordance with the TEI Guidelines.</p>
     </encodingDesc>
     <profileDesc>
        <langUsage>
           <language ident="en">English</language>
        </langUsage>
     </profileDesc>
     <revisionDesc>
     <list><item><date when="2017-11-26" resp="#rnes">26 Nov 2017</date>Encoding shell drafted.</item>
        <item><date when="2020-09-26">26 September 2020</date><!--correct the date and fill in what work you did.--></item>
        <item><date when="2020-09-29">29 September 2020</date><!--correct the date and fill in what work you did.--></item>
        </list>
     </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div type="volume" n="5">
            <div type="page" n="165">
               <p><add cause="otherhand"><hi rend="Gray_Pencil">p.397-8</hi></add><del type="wavy_line"><del rend="Gray_Pencil" hand="Author">of Duncan Ingraham Esq., gentleman of Concord village,</del></del> who built his slave a house and gave him permission to live in Walden woods.<add cause="ME">about 5-6 illegible words</add> Some say he was a Guinea negro.</p>
           
               <p>There are those who remember his little hatch among the walnut, and a tree which he let grow up till he should be old and need them, but a younger whiter speculator got them at last.<add cause="Author"><hi rend="Author's_Ink">he too however occupies an equally narrow house at present</hi></add></p>
               
               <p><add cause="otherhand"><hi rend="Gray_Pencil">Notes between the two paragraphs that weave between and in the sentences, illegible.</hi></add></p>
               <p>But here by the very corner of my field still near a town, Zipha, colored woman had her little house where she spun linen for the town folk, making the Walden woods ring with her shrill singing, for she had a loud and notable voice, at length, in the war of 1812, her dwelling was set on fire by English soldiers, prisoners on patrole, <add cause="Author"><hi rend="Author's_Ink">when she was away.</hi></add>and her cat and dog and hens were all burned up together. She lead a hard life and somewhat</p>
            
            </div>
            </div>

         
      </body>
     <back>
        <p>Critical Commentary</p>
        <p>	To be perfectly honest, I am not very good at reading or writing cursive. The school I went to growing up stopped teaching us when I was in the third grade. Therefore, aside from my parents teaching me a little bit and me sort of picking it up over the years I struggle with it. I am not saying I cannot read cursive, but it does take me a little bit longer to register cursive words in my brain than some people. Thoreau’s handwriting did not help the already existing struggle at all, especially with how slanted his words are and how with some words you can tell he barely picked up his pen after finishing a word before starting a new one. Smaller, more common words were easier for me to figure out, but some longer rooms did trip me up a little. I figured out maybe three-fourths of the page but there was one sentence in the middle, that started a new paragraph that for the longest time I could not figure out. After struggling and failing too many times for my taste I recruited the help of my mom. She is great with cursive, opposite of me, however, that is not the reason why I asked of her help. Years ago, she used to work at Green Bay Oncology as a medical assistant, therefore she has lots of experience reading doctors notes, and their writing can get pretty illegible. Although, without much context she was not 100 percent positive on a couple of the words, but it did help steer me in the right direction to finally figure it out.</p>
          <p>What may have helped others did not work for me. I followed the instructions to print my facsimile, grab a pen, and trace Thoreau’s handwriting in an attempt to make it my own. This step only made it more difficult for me, tracing just made his writing seem like even more scribbles to me. After this failed, I tried copying this method in a slightly different way. I copied Thoreau’s words on a blank page while looking at the facsimile all the while slowly tweaking his handwriting trying to change his style to more of my style of writing. A little more difficult and more lengthy process but it did help a lot. Somewhere during this process, I took a closer look at the facsimile on my laptop realizing that as a photo file Thoreau’s writing was clearer than what had printed. Not only that but the pencil marks that I originally thought was writing that bled through from the other side were actually penciled in by either Thoreau or someone else, although I could not read those. However, after a while I did notice that everything was written on the same side based on the direction of a few of the letter loops. Some notes were written in the same ink Thoreau used on the rest of the page, easily connecting him as the writer for those, but some notes appear to be written in pencil and for me it is too small to see a pattern between that writing and the larger bits leaving me to think it was written by some unknown editor.</p> 
           <p>As for working with the oXygen program, for a good portion of this project I was overwhelmed, it is a new program to me that came with a lot of information at once to comprehend. However, after class on the 29th (September) I believe that I have a better grasp of the process than my initial go of it, especially after being able to see examples of the different elements and attributes added because I was struggling with what needed to be added with what information.</p>
     </back>
  </text>
</TEI>